A single bullet can change history.
Enemy at the Gates is a drama, war, history film
directed by Jean-Jacques Annaud.
A Russian and a German sniper play a game of cat-and-mouse
during the Battle of Stalingrad in WWII.
Vassili Zaitsev, played by Jude Law.
Commisar Danilov, played by Joseph Fiennes.
Tania Chernova, played by Rachel Weisz.
Major König, played by Ed Harris.
Nikita Khrushchev, played by Bob Hoskins.
Koulikov, played by Ron Perlman.
Enemy at the Gates (Stalingrad in France and L'Ennemi aux portes in Canada) is a 2001 war film directed, co-written, and produced by Jean-Jacques Annaud, based on William Craig's
1973 nonfiction book Enemy at the Gates: The Battle for Stalingrad, which describes the events surrounding the Battle of Stalingrad in the winter of 1942–1943.
The screenplay was written by Annaud and Alain Godard.
The film's main character is a fictionalized version of Vasily Zaitsev, a
sniper and Hero of the Soviet Union during World War II.
It depicts a snipers' duel between Zaitsev and a Wehrmacht
sniper school director, Major Erwin König.
The cast includes Jude Law, Joseph Fiennes, Rachel Weisz, Bob Hoskins, Ed Harris, Ron
Perlman, Eva Mattes, Gabriel Marshall Thomson, and Matthias Habich.
The film explores themes of sniper, hero, winter, world war ii, stalingrad.
The tone is emotional.